Benjamin Noah

Data Scientist

💌 bnoah1216@gmail.com 📞 +1-323-428-4057 🦹 Portfolio ¡ LinkedIn 🕡 GitHub 🔮 Los Angeles, CA

Professional Summary

Data Scientist with a Master's in Economics and proven work experience. I have developed a deep understanding of predictive modeling, and data processing using Python. Ability to solve complex problems within organizations to optimize results

Skills

Python

Machine Learning Supervised Learning / Unsupervised Learning

Data Cleaning / Data Preprocessing / Modeling

Deep Learning

Database Management / Data Extraction

TernsorFlow / Keras / PyTorch

Professional Experience

Research Associate, University of California, Santa Barbara (UCSB)

09/2018 - 09/2021

- Wrote 5+ reports analyzing research papers by highlighting strengths, weaknesses, and ideas for future research using an economic perspective.
- Identified novel topics in research by synthesizing general research in the field and presented research proposals on topics in population, behavioral, and health economics.

Researcher, Cedars-Sinai Center for Outcomes Research and Education

09/2016 - 06/2018

- Designed cost-effectiveness/health decision models for various projects.
- Conducted systematic reviews and meta-analyses for several studies.
- · Organized, planned, and coordinated a national conference on medical virtual reality.
- Coordinated Institutional Review Board applications, edited and revised consent forms, and protocols to ensure compliance with organizational policies and federal laws.

Education

Data Science Bootcamp, Practicum by Yandex

2021 - 2022

M.A. in Economics, University of California, Santa Barbara

2018 - 2020

B.S. in Economics, University of Oregon

2012 - 2016

Projects

Interconnect - Notebook, To create a machine learning model to predict which customers will leave Interconnect soon.

01/2022

- Cleaned and merged 4 datasets for analysis.
- Built 5 unique models using hyperparameter tuning, scaling, and cross-validation.
- Created a Dash widget to compare models' accuracy and AUC scores.

Film Junky Union - Notebook, To create a machine learning model to automatically detect negative reviews.

12/2021

- Normalized the text using regular expressions.
- Built 5 models using a variety of different tokenizers and machine learning algorithms.
- Analyzed model performance using accuracy, F1, and ROC-AUC scores.

Publications

- Almario CV, Noah B, Jusufagic A, Lew D, Spiegel BMR. The Cost-Effectiveness of Laboratory Biomarkers for Irritable Bowel Syndrome with Diarrhea: A Framework for Payers. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol.
- Noah B, Keller MS, Mosadeghi S, Stein L, Johl S, Delshad S, Tashjian V, Lew D, Kwan J, Jusufagic A, Spiegel BMS. Impact of Remote Patient Monitoring on Clinical Outcomes: An Updated Meta-Analysis of Randomized Controlled Trials. Digital Medicine.